### CONTACT ME AT

- Residence: Q.No.124-A,Sarwal Colony, Jammu, J&K
- divyangi.mahajan17@gmail.com
- +91 7780989702
- in www.linkedin.com/in/divyangi-mahajan
- https://github.com/divyangi-mhjn/

#### TECHNOLOGIES

React JS

Redux

Javascript

Node.js

PostgreSQL

Oracle Database

Heroku

**AWS Services** 

knex.js

Java

### SKILLS SUMMARY

Team Building

DevOps Proficiency

Solution Mockups

Agile

# **DIVYANGI MAHAJAN**

### FULL STACK DEVELOPER

### PERSONAL PROFILE

Tech-savvy developer with 3+ years of experience for collaborating and working on multiple web-based projects. Passionate, hardworking coder with penchant for developing customized interfaces that factor in unique demands for accessibility, reachability and security. Organized approach to meeting multiple, concurrent deadlines.

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

#### APPLICATION DEVELOPER

TATA CONSULTANCY SERVICES | MARCH 2019 - PRESENT

- Utilized technologies like React, Redux, Node.js ,PostgresSql, Javascript, AWS Services, Openshift Platform to develop new applications using agile methodologies.
- Participated in design and planning exercises for future software rollouts.
- Resolved system test and validation problems to provide normal program functioning.
- Played major role in layout modifications to improve the functionality.
- Planned website development, converting mockups into usable web presence.

### APPLICATION DEVELOPER

SKILL LOTTO SOLUTIONS | JUN 2018 - FEB 2019

- Developed and evolved consumer-facing, multi-channel roadmap for desktop, mobile and mobile web applications.
- Worked closely with other team members in tasks such as troubleshooting and debugging.
- Provided code maintenance and system upgrades to maximize performance.
- Performed troubleshooting of technical issues within production environment.

#### **EDUCATIONAL HISTORY**

# GEETA ENGINEERING COLLEGE KURUKSHETRA UNIV.

Bachelor's In Computer Sciences | Aug 2014 - June 2018

• Received an honors degree with 79%

#### PROJECTS HIGHLIGHTS

# **Integrated Risk Assessment**

July 2021 - Present

Technologies: Node.js, ReactJs, Redux, knex.js, PostgreSql

Hosting Platform: Heroku

• This application is used to create assessment by admin for various quarters in a year which has to be filled in the the chosen receipients.

# Password Reset Utility

Feb 2021 - June 2021

Technologies: Node.js, ReactJs, Redux, knex.js, Oracle DB

Hosting Platform : Openshift

• The application is used to reset password for the selected oracle db instance for the selected user.

• The password is temporary and received through email.

# CIO Awards Application

Oct 2020 - Feb 2021

Technologies : Node.js , ReactJs, Redux, knex.js, postgresSQL, Contentful

Hosting Platform: AWS

• A web application designed to streamline selection process for various awards given to selected projects that have been nominated and accepted .

• The forms filledby the nominee included features like autosave, ruch text editors for better user experience.

# SmartdevOps Portal

April 2020 - Sep 2020

Technologies: Node.js, ReactJs, postgresSQL,Contentful

Hosting Platform: Heroku

- The web application is used to submit new proposals and manage theproposals that are ipresent in the system where different levels of status are present.
- Subscription of proposals for regular updates is also present.

### **DIA Assessment Tool**

Oct 2019 - Mar 2020

Technologies: Node.js, ReactJs, Redux, postgresSQL, Contentful

Hosting Platform: Heroku

- The web application consists of dynamic question and answers portal where users have to answer some set of questions for the admin to evaluate.
- The questions are categorized on the basis of the different groups a user belongs to.

## MIND Application

April 2019-Oct 2019

Technologies: Node.js, ReactJs, Redux, postgresSQL, Contentful, Denodo

Hosting Platform: Heroku

- This web application is an inventory system for company's internal data and classified information.
- Performance improvement algorithms were used.

# Rajshree Lotteries

June 2018 - Feb 2019

Technologies: React Js, PHP, MySQL

- This web application used to deal with the information of accounts and the lotteries a user has bought and distributed further.
- The application displays and saves excel and pdf reports generated in the application